<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<conference>
	<event_detail>
		<start_time></start_time>
	</event_detail>
	<session_detail>
		<session>
			<speaker>
				<name>Daniel Cousineau</name>
				<company>Rapp Collins</company>
				<company_link>http://www.rapp.com</company_link>
				<photo></photo>
			</speaker>
			<title>Disregard Inputs, Acquire Zend_Form</title>
			<description>Learn in-depth Zend_Form techniques to automate and power your applications forms, with or without using Zend Framework. Learn everything from setup of a form to custom elements and organizational best practices.</description>
			<track>1</track>
			<session_start>09:00</session_start>
		</session>
		<session>
			<speaker>
				<name>Stephen Fierbaugh</name>
				<company>Pioneer Bible Translators</company>
				<photo></photo>
			</speaker>
			<title>Preparing LAMP for Production</title>
			<description>
				Covers all the steps between basic installation being complete and the server officially being "live".  It is a checklist 
				of everything necessary to harden the server, and covers LogWatch, SSH, Nagios, Monit, Fail2ban, etc. in a format suitable 
				for beginners and intermediate administrators.
			</description>
			<track>2</track>
			<session_start>09:00</session_start>
		</session>
		<session>
			<speaker>
				<name>TBD</name>
				<company> </company>
				<company_link> </company_link>
				<photo></photo>
			</speaker>
			<title>TBD</title>
			<description>
			</description>
			<track>1</track>
			<session_start>10:00</session_start>
		</session>
		<session>
			<speaker>
				<name>Joe Mills</name>
				<company>lifeBlue Media</company>
				<company_link>http://lifeblue.com</company_link>
				<photo></photo>
			</speaker>
			<title>Why Developers Don't Matter</title>
			<description>
				It's all about the user! In this session we will discuss the graceful handling of client and server-side scripting and the 
				importance of design thinking at all stages in the development process. We will discuss the value of designing for the 
				user and the reality that even the smallest forms shouldn.t look like plugins. We believe design thinking should be 
				infused at all levels in the development process and the user should be the central focus of all efforts. This requires 
				a new way of thinking and encourages programmers to think more creatively and .creatives. to think more technically. 
				This embraces a broader range of disciplines and marries developers and designers in their approach to creating the
				ultimate user experience.
			</description>
			<track>2</track>
			<session_start>10:00</session_start>
		</session>
		<session>
			<speaker>
				<name>Jake Smith</name>
				<company>Rapp Collins</company>
				<company_link>http://www.rapp.com</company_link>
				<photo></photo>
			</speaker>
			<title>Unsung Heroes of PHP</title>
			<description>
				PHP is filled with many amazing functions/classes that we use daily (PDO, array_*, etc.).  There are also many 
				classes/functions that have been created to make our lives much easier, many of which are not popularized in 
				tutorials/articles.  Whether you're a developer of 6 months or 6 years there are many things that got missed.  
				I will be discussing usefulness of filter_var and the plethora of benefits when using SPL.
			</description>
			<track>1</track>
			<session_start>11:00</session_start>
		</session>
		<session>
			<speaker>
				<name>Malvik Majithia</name>
				<company>The University of Texas at Dallas</company>
				<company_link>http://utdallas.com</company_link>
				<photo></photo>
			</speaker>
			<title>Object Oriented Web Development - OOP PHP</title>
			<description>
				Many developers have had little, some or a lot of experience using OOP and PHP. While it is a great coding technique, 
				without the correct Design Patterns, there may be some difficulty when it is time to scale and expand. When it comes 
				to OOP, PHP and Design Patterns, there are some common questions such as:

				1. How do you use all 3 of them together?
				2. How can you use Object Oriented concepts and paradigms in combination with PHP, JavaScript and CSS to your advantage 
				to develop re-usable code modules for a scalable web site?
				3. What are some good resources (Object Oriented) to promote Rapid Application Development (RAD)?

				This session will discuss Object Oriented Web Development in detail as opposed to the usual Encapsulation, Polymorphism, 
				Inheritance tutorials. The basics of OOP will be briefly recapped but the main focus will be on code architecture 
				and design best practices.
			</description>
			<track>2</track>
			<session_start>11:00</session_start>
		</session>
		<session>
			<speaker>
				<name>Brian Blood</name>
				<company>MacServe</company>
				<company_link>http://macserve.net</company_link>
				<photo></photo>
			</speaker>
			<title>Anecdotal Development and Deployment</title>
			<description>
				Editing in place on the production server? Blech! No source code control? Oy vey! Developing on PHP 5.3 on your 
				local machine, but deploying on 5.2 on a production server? The Horror!

				Are you a 1-5 person shop that develops code for your company/customers? Learn about a specific example of 
				setups/workflows/policies/code constructs for team development in a simple, unified, clean manner.
			</description>
			<track>1</track>
			<session_start>13:30</session_start>
		</session>
		<session>
			<speaker>
				<name>Chris Christensen</name>
				<company>AllPlayers.com</company>
				<company_link>http://allplayers.com</company_link>
				<photo></photo>
			</speaker>
			<title>Drupal</title>
			<description>
				"Come for the software, stay for the community" - Patterns for developing sophisticated websites (not to mention quickly) 
				with Drupal, the technology now responsible for powering Whitehouse.gov, Economist, Examiner, and many other high profile 
				web presences. In this talk we will quickly discuss how to get up and running in the LAMP stack, then move onto some 
				basic site building with common "contrib" modules; additional coverage will focus on how to handle Dev->Stage->Prod.
			</description>
			<track>2</track>
			<session_start>13:30</session_start>
		</session>
		<session>
			<speaker>
				<name>Steve Iboubi</name>
				<company>SoftLayer Technologies, Inc.</company>
				<company_link>http://softlayer.com</company_link>
				<photo></photo>
			</speaker>
			<title>Scaling Your Application</title>
			<description>
				This workshop will focus on auto-scaling an application using SoftLayer cloud service.
			</description>
			<track>1</track>
			<session_start>14:30</session_start>
		</session>
		<session>
			<speaker>
				<name>Chris Koenig</name>
				<company>Microsoft</company>
				<company_link>http://microsoft.com</company_link>
				<photo></photo>
			</speaker>
			<title>Using PHP and MySQL to Build Applications with Windows Azure</title>
			<description>
				Come learn how to build rich, multi-tier applications in the cloud using PHP and MySQL, taking advantage of new 
				Windows Azure features. This session will cover using PHP, MySQL, and memcached in Windows Azure.
			</description>
			<track>2</track>
			<session_start>14:30</session_start>
		</session>
		<session>
			<speaker>
				<name>Randy Hoyt</name>
				<company>Imaginuity</company>
				<company_link>http://www.imaginuity.com</company_link>
				<photo></photo>
			</speaker>
			<title>Extending and Scaling WordPress</title>
			<description>
			    WordPress is an effective platform for powering large web sites with various types of content and structured 
			    data. In this case study, Randy Hoyt will share from his experience developing a network of shopping center 
			    web sites on WordPress for a large property management company. He will explore the newer WordPress 3.x features, 
			    its child theme architecture, custom plugins, caching techniques, and cloud hosting infrastructure used to 
			    extend and scale WordPress for this project.
			</description>
			<track>1</track>
			<session_start>15:30</session_start>
		</session>
		<session>
			<speaker>
				<name>Kevin Schroeder</name>
				<company>Zend</company>
				<company_link>http://zend.com</company_link>
				<photo></photo>
			</speaker>
			<title>Do you Queue?</title>
			<description>
				There has been a lot of talk over the past several years about the difference between performance and scalability. 
				When talking about building a scalable application queuing is a concept that many PHP developers are not overly 
				familiar with. In this talk we will demonstrate some of these principles using the Zend Server Job Queue.
			</description>
			<track>2</track>
			<session_start>15:30</session_start>
		</session>
		<session>
			<speaker>
				<name>Vic Cherubini</name>
				<company>Leftnode Software, Inc.</company>
				<company_link>http://leftnode.com</company_link>
				<photo></photo>
			</speaker>
			<title>Using Dependency Injection for Proper Unit Testing</title>
			<description>
				 If you're not unit testing, you should be. This topic will cover manual dependency injection, why it's essential for 
				 unit testing, and how to use it with your code. It will cover both writing unit tested code from scratch and taking an 
				 existing class and refactoring it with unit tests and dependency injection. I'll start off with some code I've written 
				 and how I built it with tests, show where other objects are injected and why. Then I'll pull up an old dirty class 
				 and refactor it live with DI.
			</description>
			<track>1</track>
			<session_start>16:30</session_start>
		</session>
		<session>
			<speaker>
				<name>Bob Majdak</name>
				<company>Ardent.Com, Inc</company>
				<company_link>http://ardent.com</company_link>
				<photo></photo>
			</speaker>
			<title>PHP-GTK</title>
			<description>
				Setting up and building PHP-GTK applications on the desktop workspace. Look ma, no webserver!
			</description>
			<track>2</track>
			<session_start>16:30</session_start>
		</session>
	</session_detail>
</conference>
